（ビショップ）真方ジンの　空白の１年に
関する調査ですが→
Regarding the one-year gap in Makata Jin's past,
断片的な足取りは
つかめたものの→
いまだ　全容は
明らかになっておりません。
we still haven't found any clues.
"Puzzles are chains. Puzzles are mirrors," huh?
（ルーク・盤城・クロスフィールド）
「パズルは鎖　パズルは鏡」か…。
は？
カイトから報告があったんだ。→
Excuse me?
Kaito reported it.
Apparently, Raetsel said that.
レイツェルが　そう言っていたって。
We've got nothing on her past either.
彼女の素性についても
まだ何も…。
回想
（真方ジン）ルーク。　パズルは本当に
あっていいものなのかな？
Rook.
Are puzzles really necessary?
（ジン）
君は　パズルと出会えて幸せかい？
Are you happy to have encountered puzzles?
I Just Get That Feeling
（大門カイト）ったく…　分かんねえな。
Jeez.
I don't get it.
（井藤ノノハ）レイツェルさんの事だよね。
You mean Raetsel, right?
回想
（レイツェル）私の知っているジンだけが
本当のジン！→
No! The Jin I know is the only real Jin!
君のジンは
ただの　まやかしよ！
You only dreamed that Jin!
あの目は本気だった。
She was being serious.
あいつが　うそをついているとは
思えねえ。
I don't think she was lying.
うん　私も。　でも…　だとしたら→
Yeah, I feel the same way.
But then is it also true that Jin hated puzzles?
ジンさんが　パズルを憎んでた
っていうのも本当なのかな？
Not a chance in hell.
それは　絶対
ありえねえ。
くそっ…
一体どうなってやがるんだ？
Dammit.
What's going on here?
We should look for that answer together.
（ルーク）その答えは
僕たちで探すしかないよ。
ルーク！
Rook?
（レイツェル）下手くそなパズル。
That puzzle's so lame.
それじゃあ
憎む価値すらないわよね。
It's not even worth hating, is it?
（ジン）
そのブローチ…　もしかして　僕が？
Did I give you that broach?
Have you remembered?
思い出したの!?
いや…　ただ　そんな気が…。
No, I just had that impression...
アハッ。　やっぱり
ブローチつけてきて正解だった！→
I knew putting the broach on was the right choice!
I just knew it!
何だか　予感がしたのよね。
やっぱり　私と一緒に来ない？
もっと記憶が戻るかも。
Wanna come with me? Maybe more of your memories will return that way!
そ…　それは…。
Well...
昔の事　思い出したくないの？
You don't want to remember?
決まり！　じゃあ　あとで
迎えに来るから待っててね。
Then it's a date!
I'll pick you up later! Just wait for me!
（エニグマ）ジンを迎える準備？
Get ready to pick up Jin?
我らの盟主をお迎えするのは
大歓迎だが…。
As delighted as I would be to welcome our messiah,
記憶が戻るまで　大門カイトに預けて
おくんじゃなかったのかい？
I believe we were going to leave him in Daimon Kaito's care until his memories returned.
[無線]（レイツェル）何それ？　知らな～い。
What are you even talking about?
ん？
[無線]（通話の切れる音）
やれやれ…　困った子猫だ。
Oh my. What a troublesome little kitten.
（軸川ソウジ）ルーク管理官が　レイツェルを？
Chief Rook took Raetsel?
And Kaito too.
はい。　カイトも一緒に。
（逆之上ギャモン）どこへ行ったんだ？
Where'd they go?
それが…
３人で話がしたいって…。
"We want to talk alone."
Come on!
（キュービック・Ｇ）そんな！
心配ないよ　キュービック君。
No worries, Cubik.
（解道バロン）管理官の事です。　何か
考えがあるに違いありません。
It's the Chief we're talking about. It's all probably just part of some plan.
でも！
（アナ・グラム）うん…　アナは心配。
But still!
I'm worried.
そうだよ！　レイツェルが
一緒だなんて危険だよ。
Yeah! Having Raetsel around is dangerous!
ううん　あの子じゃないの。
えっ？
It's not her.
（アナ）あの子が来てからのカイト→
I feel like ever since she arrived, Kaito's gone back to the way he was when I first met him.
アナが初めて会った頃のカイトに
戻ってるような気がする。
初めて会った頃？
When you first met him?
パズルが好きで　パズルが嫌いなカイトに。
あ…。
He loved and hated puzzles at the same time.
で　ジンは　どうしてんだ？
And where is Jin?
自分の部屋にいますが　何か？
In his room. Why?
Just asking.
別に。
カイト…。
Kaito...
（ルーク）はい　君の分。
These are for you.
I'll pass! I hope that's not what you called me here for!
要らないわよ。
そんなもののために
呼び出したわけじゃないでしょ？
あったかいうちの方が　うめえぞ。
Eat them while they're hot!
You can't get stuff like this every day.
（ルーク）ふだんは　こういうの
食べられなくてね。
ジンの事で
話があるんじゃなかったの？
I thought you wanted to talk about Jin.
ああ　そうだった。
何だよ　ルーク　話って？
Oh, right. What did you wanna talk about, Rook?
昔　こうして
パズルしたよね。　ジンと３人で。
We used to puzzle together like this with Jin. The three of us.
ああ　そうだったな…。
Yeah.
I remember that.
やっぱり
ジンが　パズルを憎むだなんて→
There's no way Jin would ever say he hated puzzles.
言うはずがねえ。
But Raetsel, I don't think you're lying either.
でも　レイツェル　お前が
うそをついてるとも思えねえんだ。
当然よ。　それに　カイト…　君だって
パズルの事　憎んでたんじゃないの？
Of course not.
And Kaito, didn't you hate puzzles as well?
君の両親
パズルで命を落としたんでしょ？
Weren't your parents killed by a puzzle?
（レイツェル）ジンから聞いたわ。→
Jin told me about the hate you harbor for puzzles, Kaito.
カイト…　君の中にも
パズルへの憎しみはある。→
ジンにはないと
どうして言えるの？
Why are you sure Jin isn't the same way?
君もよ　ルーク。→
And you, Rook?
オルペウスの腕輪に飲み込まれて→
You made so many dangerous puzzles under the control of Orpheus's Armlet.
次々と危険なパズルを造り出した。
君の言うとおりかもしれない。→
You might be right.
パズルは　本当に
あっていいものなのか…。
Are puzzles really necessary?
Jin's asked me that before.
実は　僕も以前　ジンに
そう言われた事があるんだ。
ルーク!?
（レイツェル）フフッ。
Rook?
（ルーク）それから
ジンは　こうも言った。→
Jin also said, "Puzzles are chains. Puzzles are mirrors."
「パズルは鎖　パズルは鏡」と…。
その言葉
ジンが　レイツェルに言った…。
But Jin said that to Raetsel...
僕も言われたんだよ。
同じ言葉をね。
And to me too.
The same things.
それが何だっていうのよ。
So what?
あれは　ある夏の日だった。
It was on a summer day.
偶然　僕とジンが
２人きりになった事があって…。
Jin and I just happened to be alone.
回想
（ジン）ルーク。　パズルは本当に
あっていいものなのかな？
Rook.
Are puzzles really necessary?
君は　パズルと出会えて
幸せかい？
Are you happy to have encountered puzzles?
あ…。　楽しい。
They're fun.
悲しいパズル　恐ろしいパズルも
あるかもしれない。
What if there were sad and terrible puzzles?
それでも…
それでも楽しいよ！
They'd still be fun!
要らないパズルなんて　ないよ！
あったとしても　それは　きっと→
There's no such thing as an unnecessary puzzle!
Even if there are puzzles like that, I'm sure...
それを作った人が悪いんだ！
I'm sure that it's the person who made them's fault!
You're right. Sorry, sorry.
そうだよな…。　ごめん　ごめん！→
時々　寂しそうな顔を
しているだろ。→
I make these sad faces every now and then,
気になって　つい　変な事を
聞いてしまった。　悪かったな。
and now I've even asked you some stupid questions.
Forgive me.
（ジン）そう。　ルークの言うとおり
全ては人間次第。→
It's just as you said. It all depends on the person.
パズルは鎖で　パズルは鏡なんだ。
Puzzles can be chains or even mirrors.
鎖で…　鏡？　どういう意味？
Chains? Mirrors?
What does that mean?
それも　パズルさ。
That's a puzzle too.
（ルーク）僕には　まだ
その答えは分からない。
I still don't know the answer for that.
「パズルは人を縛り
見たくない自分を映し出すもの」。
Puzzles imprison people and show them their most detestable side.
ジンは　そう言いたかったのよ。
That's Jin's point.
本当に　そうなのかな？
Is it really?
I've been with Jin all this time.
私は
ジンと　ずっと一緒にいたのよ。
I know everything about him.
ジンの事なら全部　分かってるわ。
（ルーク）それじゃあ…　これも？
Then, do you know this?
Boy X? Is that from Jin?
青年Ｘ！
じゃあ　そのパズルは　ジンの!?
（レイツェル）ジン！→
Jin!
ハァ…。　パズル作ってるの？
パズラーを懲らしめるため？
Are you making a puzzle again?
To make puzzlers suffer?
I wonder.
（ジン）さあ…　どうかな？
Where did you get that?
どうして　そのパズルを…。
僕は　ジンの空白の１年間　つまり
君と行動を共にしていた間の→
I looked into Jin's whereabouts during the blank year that he spent with you.
ジンの足取りを追っていた。→
データに残っている　ジンの旅の痕跡
それは→
The records of his travels showed his heroic struggles against Fools' Puzzles.
愚者のパズルとの
壮絶な戦いの連続だった。
But that wasn't all.
でも
それだけじゃなかったんだよ。
Look at what I found in a newspaper photograph.
（ルーク）ある新聞写真に写り込んで
いたのを　偶然　発見した。
（ルーク）ジンは　つらい戦いの中で
子供たちに→
Amidst a fierce battle, he tried to teach children how fun puzzles can be.
パズルの楽しさを
伝えようとしていたんだ。
（レイツェル）うそよ！
そんな写真　でたらめよ！
No!
That photo's a fake!
そのパズルは　ジンが
パズラーを懲らしめるための→
Jin made those puzzles full of traps to—
罠を仕掛け…。
（パズルを外す音）
There are no traps in here.
罠？　んなもん　どこにもないぜ。
あっ…。
あったけえ　いいパズルだ。
It's a nice, warm puzzle.
やっぱり　俺の…
俺たちの知ってるジンだぜ。
Made by the Jin I... we know.
愚者のパズルと　子供たち
２つの間で→
Fools' puzzles and children...
There might've been uncertainty in Jin's heart.
ジンの心は揺れていたの
かもしれない。
だから　「パズルは　あってもいいと
思うか」なんて→
I guess that's why he asked you if puzzles are really necessary.
お前に聞いちまったのかもな　ルーク。
うっ…。　そ…　そんな事…。
No way!
僕たちも　君も　ジンの全てを
知ってるわけじゃない。
Neither we nor you know everything about Jin.
「パズルを憎め」。　ジンは本当に
そう言ったのかもな。
"I hate puzzles."
He might have said so. But behind that...
でも　その裏には…。
ああ。
Yeah. But he may have had reasons we don't know about to say that.
僕たちの知らない事情が
あったのかも。
一緒に探さないか？　レイツェル。
３人で力を合わせて→
Wouldn't you help us search, Raetsel?
The three of us together can find out the truth about Jin's past.
ジンの過去を…
真実を突き止めるんだ。
Give me a break!
だ…　誰が！
大門カイト！　君はパズルを憎んでいた。
Daimon Kaito! You hated puzzles!
ルーク・盤城・クロスフィールド！　君は
人殺しのパズルを造っていた。→
Rook Banjo Crossfield! You made puzzles to kill people!
Jin hated puzzles! That is the truth!
ジンも　パズルを憎んでた！
それが真実よ！
僕の過去は否定しないよ。
I won't deny my past.
でも　ジンの真実を
勝手に決めつける事は許さない。
But I won't let you just decide the truth about Jin.
何ですって!?
What?
Very well.
いいわ。　だったら教えてあげる。
I'll show you the puzzles that Jin taught me to hate the most.
私が　ジンから教わった
憎むべきパズル→
この世で最も恐ろしいパズルをね。
The most fearsome puzzles in the world.
ハァ…。
カイト　帰ってこなかったなあ。
Kaito didn't come back...
ジンさん　何してるんですか？
Jin? What are you doing?
このパズル　どう思う？
下手なパズル…　かな？
What do you think about these puzzles?
Are they lame?
いや～　私に聞かれても…。
パズル　苦手なんで。
Well, I think you asked the wrong person.
I'm really not good with puzzles...
そうなのかい？
あっ！　でも　なんか…　その…→
Oh, you aren't?
Well... I mean, this one's really cute and fun looking!
あっ　なんか　かわいくて…
楽しそうなパズルですよね～。
Is that a Fool's Puzzle?
こいつは…　愚者のパズルか。
（ルーク）こんな所にも　あったなんて。
There was one here?
（レイツェル）私が知る　この世で最も
危険で恐ろしいパズル。→
I know.
This is the most dangerous and fearful puzzle.
あのジンでさえ
解放するのを諦めたほどのね。
Even Jin gave up releasing it.
ジンが!?
Jin did?
（レイツェル）ジンが憎み　恐怖したパズル。
これが真実よ。→
A puzzle Jin hated and feared. This is the truth.
ルーク・盤城・クロスフィールド。
なんなら　自分で確かめてみる？
Rook Banjo Crossfield, why don't you check for yourself?
いいだろう。
ルーク!?
Fine.
Rook!
（ルーク）パズルは鎖で…　パズルは鏡。→
"Puzzles are chains. Puzzles are mirrors."
僕は　あの言葉の意味が
知りたいんだ。
I want to know what those words meant.
ジンが挑んだパズルに挑めば→
If I get a taste of the puzzle he fought, maybe I'll get closer to understanding his feelings.
ジンの思いに
近づけるかもしれない。
あそこが　ゴールか…。
Is that the exit?
We're above a depthless abyss, and there's no escape.
下は　底なしの谷で　逃げ場なし。→
かといって　無理やり
違う柱に移ろうとすれば→
Yet, blades prevent you from breaking into other platforms.
鋭い槍が　待ち構えている。
つまり　出口に行きたければ→
Which means that those seeking the exit must solve this puzzle.
このパズルを解くしかない
というわけだ。
パズルタイムの始まりよ。
It's puzzle time.
I see, so if I stand on a column, its height changes.
（ルーク）なるほど…
石柱に乗ると　高さが変わる。→
じゃあ　この数字は…。
What about these numbers then?
The columns all have numbers.
（レイツェル）石柱には　それぞれ
数字が割りふられているの。
ルークの持ってる石板に書かれた
数字が　ヒントになってるわ。
The numbers on the plate Rook has are the hint.
（ルーク）初めの石柱の数字は　１４。
次は　４６。→
The first column's number was 14.
The next was 46.
恐らく　これは
石柱の　もともとの高さと→
These probably show the number of the column's starting and end heights.
移動先の高さを示している。
So what if there's only one digit?
じゃあ　数字が１桁の場合は…。
な…!?
ルーク！
Rook!
危ねえ！
あのまま乗っていたら…。
That was close! If he would've been on that...
くっ…。
数字が１桁の場合は　上昇。
If there's only one digit, you get vaulted to the ceiling.
天井に激突して　行き止まり。
それに　考える時間にも制限がある
という　おまけ付きか。→
There's no time to think either.
前の　３２に行けば
１桁の２にしか進めなくなる。→
If I go to the 32 ahead, I can only move to the next 2.
ここは　３５に…。
35 is my choice.
ウフフッ。　ルールは理解したようね。
Looks like he understands the rules.
Rook...
ルーク…。
（レイツェル）君の両親のように→
What if a puzzle took your friend just as one took your parents?
大切な友達も
パズルに奪われちゃうかもね。
私も　昔　このパズルで…。
I've faced this puzzle too.
（レイツェル）あのパズル…。
（ジン）ん？
That puzzle...
（レイツェル）
あのパズル　怖くて解けなかった。
That puzzle was so scary that I couldn't solve it.
あのパズルだけは　俺も解けなかった。
That's the only puzzle I couldn't solve either.
えっ　ジンも？
ああ。→
You either?
Yeah. I've never seen such a dreadful Fools' Puzzle before.
あんなに恐ろしい愚者のパズルは
生まれて初めてだよ。
そうなんだ…。
Oh, I see.
You must never go near such a dangerous puzzle alone, Raetsel.
（ジン）
レイツェルは　あんな危険なパズルに→
二度と
１人で近づいちゃ駄目だぞ。
But I'm your assistan—
でも　私は　ジンの手伝いを…。
（ジン）ほら。
Here.
あっ…。　これは？
What?
俺のお守りだ。　これからは
レイツェルに持っていてほしい。→
A charm. I want you to have it.
俺が　愚者のパズルに挑んでいる間→
Wait for me when I challenge Fools' Puzzles, and pray for my safety, okay?
俺の無事を祈って
待っててくれよな。
あの　ジンの優しい笑顔も…
パズルに奪われた。
Puzzles took that gentle smile of Jin's from me.
心の声
（ルーク）このあと進める
石柱は　６と６１。→
I can proceed to 6 or 61.
But if I choose 6,
しかし　６に進めば…。→
数字が１桁の石柱は
天井に激突する。→
like with all single digit numbers, I'll get squashed against the ceiling.
なら　６１に…。→
Then 61?
いや　６１に行っても
先へは進めない。→
But even if I go to 61, I won't be able to go any further.
That means I can't go any further than this.
つまり　これ以上　先へは進めない
という事になる。
（ルーク）
このパズルには…　答えがないのか？
Does this puzzle have no solution?
これで分かったでしょ。
Do you see now?
パズルは　大切なものを奪う
憎むべき存在なのよ。
Puzzles are nothing but terrible tools to take what we hold dear from us.
カイト　あなたは
また　パズルに奪われるのよ。
Kaito, puzzles are gonna take something from you again.
今度は　大切な友達を…。
This time, your friend.
違うな。
えっ？
No.
お前には聞こえないのか？
この愚者のパズルの　泣き声が…。
Can't you hear
how this Fools' Puzzle is crying?
パズルの…　泣き声？
The puzzle is crying?
父さんと母さんを奪った
あのパズルを解いた時も→
When I solved the puzzle that took my parents,
俺には聞こえたんだ。
解放されたパズルの　喜ぶ声が…。
I could hear how happy it was to be free.
こいつだって→
I'm sure this one didn't become a puzzle that kills because it wanted to either.
なりたくて　人殺しのパズルに
なったわけじゃねえ。
悪いのは　パズルではなく
パズルを作った人間なんだ。
The puzzle isn't the one to blame.
It's the person who made it.
ルーク！　パズルの声を聞くんだ！
Rook! Listen to the voice of the puzzle!
Free it from its suffering!
そして…　こいつを
苦しみから解き放ってやれ！
Right. I get it now, Kaito.
そうだ。　そうだったね　カイト。
心の声
（ルーク）恐れるな…
パズルと向き合うんだ！
Don't be afraid. Face the puzzle.
On column 6, there's a piece of the board. That means...
６の床に　石板のかけらが…。
という事は…。
くっ…　僕は…。
I'll...
trust you!
（ルーク）あなたを信じる！
ルーク！
Rook!
I see! Some columns move downwards!
そうか！　下に降りる石柱も
あったのか。
くっ…。
（ルーク）ここから進むべきは
５…　いや　３だ。→
From here, I can move to 5... No, to 3.
だが　３が下降したら　１２。→
But if 3 descends, I'll go to 12.
上昇したら…　７８だ！
And if I rise, I'll go to 78!
よっしゃ！
まさか　あの難所を
乗り越えるなんて…。
Hell yeah!
There's no way he could get past that!
フゥ…。　よし　あと少し。
Just a little more left!
そ…　そんな…。
ったく！　ひやひやさせやがって。
No way.
Geez, I almost pissed myself there.
（ルーク）ジン　そして　カイト
２人が僕を救ってくれたんだ。
Jin and Kaito.
You two saved me.
俺とジンが？
Jin and I?
Back then, I wasn't sure which column I should get on.
（ルーク）あの時　目の前の石柱に
飛び乗るべきか迷った。→
故意か偶然かは分からない。
でも　あれは→
Call it good luck or an accident if you want,
but I think that was left from when Jin released that puzzle.
ジンが　あのパズルを解放した時に
残されたものだと思う。
That's a lie! Jin couldn't solve that puz—
そんなの　でたらめよ！　ジンは
あのパズルは解けなかったって…。
（ルーク）うそをついてたんだよ。
あ…。
He lied to you.
I bet he just didn't want to let you near some dangerous puzzle.
きっと　お前を　危険なパズルに
近づけたくなかったんだろうな。
（ルーク）
カイトの声が　ジンの残したヒントが
僕の迷いを打ち消してくれた。
Kaito's voice and the hint Jin left behind erased my hesitation.
やっと分かったよ。　「パズルは鎖」。
Now I understand.
Puzzles are chains. Chains that steadily connect people together.
鎖は　人と人とを
しっかり　つないでくれるもの。
Puzzles connect people?
人と人とを　つなぐ？
（ルーク）君だって　パズルで　ジンと
つながっているじゃないか。
あ…。
Aren't you connected to Jin through puzzles?
じゃあ　「鏡」ってのは？
Then what about the mirror part?
（ルーク）恐怖におびえた目で
見つめれば　恐怖が…。
If you look at it with fear, you'll only see something fearful.
But if you seek the truth, you'll find the solution, huh?
真実を見抜こうと　見つめれば
真実が映るってわけか。
そんな事…。　ジンの思いを
勝手に決めつけないで！
Who are you to decide how Jin feels?
（ルーク）そう。　君と同じさ。
あ…。
Someone just like you.
君も　僕も　カイトも
こんなにも　ジンの事を知らない。
You, Kaito, and I know hardly anything about Jin.
ああ。　やっぱり　力を合わせて
一緒に　ジンの真実…。
Yeah. We should work together to find the tru—
Cut the crap!
ふざけないで！　ジンの事なら
私が知ってる。　それで十分よ！
I know the truth about Jin! That enough for me!
じゃあ　俺たちだけで
やるしかねえな。
Then we've gotta do it by ourselves.
ジンの過去に秘められた
この複雑で難解なパズルを→
I'll solve this complex and difficult puzzle hidden in Jin's past.
絶対に解いてみせる。
フン…　まあ好きにしたら？
Do whatever you want.
心の声
（レイツェル）だって　ジンは
もう　私の所に…。
Jin's already mine.
（レイツェル）
あっ　ジン！　迎えに来たわよ。
Jin! I've come to pick you up!
さあ　私と一緒に行きましょ。
Come with me now!
Sorry. I can't go with you.
すまない…。
君とは一緒に行けない。
（レイツェル）あ…　どうして!?
Why not?
（ジン）
君には…　何かが欠けている…。
You lack something.
なぜか…　そんな気がするんだ。→
I get that feeling.
すまない。
Sorry.
まだ…　そう言うんだ…。
You're still saying that?
回想
（ジン）君には　何かが欠けている。
You lack something.
Preview